Mohsen Saeidi

CONTACT E-mail: saeidi.mhsn@gmail.com

INFORMATION Skype: sd.mohsen

Webpage: mohsensaeidi.ir



PROFESSIONAL

SUMMARY

Versatile Java Developer experienced with the full software development lifecycle and comfortable working within Agile development frameworks. Organized and hardworking team player with strong verbal and written communication skills. Prepared to bring 8 years of related experience to a challenging position.

SOFTWARE

SKILLS

- Core Java Experiences
- Software Development Lifecycle
- Automating Unit Testing
- Agile Development Methodology
- System Design & Software Architecture
- Excellent Communication Skills
- Excellent Problem-Solving Abilities
- Reviewing Code
- DevOps Principles
- Linux Administration
- Enterprise Applications
- Aspect Oriented Programming
- CI/CD
- Bug Tracking, Troubleshooting
- J2EE Architecture Specialist
- Database Design
- New Employee Mentoring
- Planning & Implementation
- Requirements Analysis
- Micro Service Architecture

- Spring Framework
- ORM, Hibernate/JPA
- Java 11
- Oracle DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Maven, Gradle
- JSF, MyFaces, PrimeFaces, JSP
- Apache2, Tomcat
- Redis
- RabbitMQ
- Rest, Soap Services
- SSL Certificate
- C, C++, C#
- React, Redux, Nodejs
- Html, CSS, JavaScript
- Python
- ELK Stack
- Git, SVN
- CAS/SSO
- Hadoop, Spark
- MongoDB

EDUCATION

Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Master of Science in Computer Networks Sep 2016- Jun 2019

University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology 2011-2015

Hatef High School, Tehran, Iran

Diploma in Physics and Mathematics discipline 2007-2011

EMPLOYMENT

Technical Java Lead at Dotin, Tehran, Iran

June 2017-Present

Senior Java Developer and Lead Architect at Limoome June 2015- May 2016

Software Engineer at Fanap June 2013- May 2017

Software Engineer at Karnik System Shargh August 2012-June 2013

HONORS AND

Stack Overflow more than 3.8k reputation (https://bit.ly/2UCxsy0).

AWARDS

16th position in Iran university entrance MSc exam of Computer Engineering.

2th position in Iran Robocup 2D Soccer Simulation competitions 2009.

2th position in Khwarizmi Robotics Festival Junior 2D Soccer Simulation League

2009.

LANGUAGE

SKILLS

Persian: native **English:** fluent

Arabic: familiar

NOTABLE

PROJECTS

Dotin Core Insurance: A general insurance system solution web enterprise that consists of many modules as insurance setup, servicing and quotation, financial and accounting, claim processing and claim recovery etc.

Technologies: J2EE, CAS/SSO, Spring framework, Hibernate, Servelts/JSP, JSF, Oracle database, Tomcat, Maven, SOAP, Jasper Reports, RESTful, Git, lots more.

Duties: I'm technical java lead currently. My major duties are lead in software design, secure quality of team deliverables, Implementing the best practices and coding standards of the project and also coach and help team members.

Recommendation System Based On Network Coding: My M.Sc. Project which using network coding algorithms to improve performance of map reduce frameworks and implemented on recommendation systems.

Technologies: Hadoop, Spark, Java, Python, AWS, Star Cluster.

Limoome: A Telegram bot that get all medical information from users and generates a diet based on their metabolism.

Technologies: Java, Spring boot, Hibernate/JPA, PostgreSQL, Jasper Reports, RESTful, Spring MVC, AWS, Heroku, Office 365, Git.

Duties: Completely done by myself.

Ghasedak Book: A desktop application for book stores that include all steps from inventory management to sale invoice and other modules.

Technologies: C#, NHibernate, Microsoft SQL Server, Crystal Reports.

Duties: Completely done by myself.

Dotin POS Driver: A driver for Dotin POS that provides users to use their debit card without entering price or any other information.

Technologies: Java Applet, JQuery, Node.js, nssm, Servlets/JSP, CSS, HTML.

Duties: Completely done by myself.